MEDITERRANEAN SEA
60 MILES SOUTH OF MARSEILLES
[Shouting in Italian]
[Ominous instrumental music]
[Rhythmic music]
THE BOURNE IDENTITY
[Rhythmic music continues]
SAILORS: [In Italian]
What a mess.
You've never seen a dead man before?
Put a blanket on him. Cover him.
I'm coming.
Be careful.
One minute. I'll be right there. Cover him.
[Suspenseful music]
000-7-1 7-1 2-0-1 4-26
Gemeinschaft Bank Zurich
BOURNE: What the hell
are you doing to me?
[Giancarlo protests]
BOURNE: What are you doing?
Goddamn it! Where am I?
GIANCARLO: A boat! A fishing boat.
You were in the water.
We pulled you out.
BOURNE: What water?
GIANCARLO: You were shot. See?
There are the bullets.
GIANCARLO: Look, there is a number
for a bank. Why was it in your hip?
BOURNE: My hip?
-Why was it in your hip?
-My hip.
Yeah, in your hip under the skin.
BOURNE: Oh, God.
BOURNE: What are you doing with me?
GIANCARLO: You need to rest.
Please. Lie down.
I'm a friend. I'm your friend.
My name is Giancarlo.
Who are you?
GIANCARLO: What's your name?
What's your name?
BOURNE: I don't know.
BOURNE: Oh, God.
GIANCARLO: Lie down.
CENTRAL INTELLIGENCE AGENCY
LANGLEY, VIRGINIA
[General office chatter]
It's been confirmed, sir. Mission failed.
[Rhythmic instrumental music]
BOURNE: [In French]
Do you know who I am?
I do not know who I am.
BOURNE: [In Dutch]
Tell me who I am.
If you know who I am...
Please stop messing around...
...and tell me.
[Speaking in Italian]
GIANCARLO: If you want to eat, get in there.
BOURNE: Based on these charts,
I think I may have been closer to the coast.
What is this? You tie these knots?
GIANCARLO: So, it starts to come back?
BOURNE: No, it doesn't.
The knot's like everything else.
I found the rope and I did it.
Same way I can read.
I can write. I can add, subtract.
I can make coffee.
BOURNE: I can shuffle cards, play chess.
GIANCARLO: Yes, it will come back.
No, it's not coming back, goddamn it!
That's the point!
I'm down here looking through this,
all this shit!
For two weeks I'm down here.
It's not working.
I don't even know what to look for.
You need to rest. It will come back.
BOURNE: What if it doesn't come back?
We get in there tomorrow,
I don't even have a name.
[Seagulls chirp, bells ring]
[Ship's horn resounds]
It's not much,
but it should get you to Switzerland.
Thank you.
[Soft rhythmic instrumental music]
ZURICH COPS: [In German]
Can't you read the signs?
On your feet...let's go...right now.
The park is closed.
There's no sleeping in the park.
BOURNE: All right.
Let's see some identification.
BOURNE: No, I don't--
Come on...your papers.
I don't have any papers. I lost my....
I've lost them...my papers...they are lost.
Ok...let's go...put your hands up.
...I just need to sleep...
[Commands angrily in German]
These people have threatened my family.
My babies.
So I'm telling you,
when the evidence is clear...
...I will have a nice story
for you to read about.
And all my friends out there,
you will read about yourselves.
If you want to play this game...
...after I have been reasonable,
I will show you.
That's Nykwana Wombosi speaking in Paris
the day before yesterday.
He was an irritation before he took power,
a problem...
...when he was in power,
and he's been a disaster for us in exile.
He's writing a book
about the Agency's history in Africa.
He's going to name names.
It's basically a shaedown.
He's demanding the Agency's help.
He wants us to put him back in power
in six months, or else.
This interview, and I'll make the tape
available to whoever wants it...
...he goes on to claim that he's just survived
an assassination attempt.
He says it's us. He says he's got proof.
The Director wants to know
if there's any truth...
...in this accusation.
I've already assured him there's nobody
that recless on my senior staff.
ABBOTT: I was recalling a conversation
we had some time ago.
Taling about Treadstone.
I seem to remember Wombosi's name
might have come up.
I'm not sure what we're talking about.
Someone tried to take him out.
Tried and failed.
Was this Treadstone?
You're asking me a direct question?
Yes.
I thought you were never gonna do that.
What happened?
Well, we lost the communication
with our man.
This was almost two weeks ago.
CONKLIN: We've worked around the clock.
We've been sleeping down there.
We're doing everything we can.
ABBOTT: And you don't let me know this?
CONKLIN: You never wanted to before.
You never made a mistake before.
GEMEINSCHAFT BANK
ZURICH SWITZERLAND
[Bustling traffic]
[In German]
What can I do for you?
Yes, I'm here about a numbered account.
If you just enter your account number here,
I'll direct you to an appropriate officer.
[Speaking in German]
[Suspenseful music]
PASSPORT - United States of America
My name is Jason Bourne.
I live in Paris.
[Inaudible talking outside room]
[Suspenseful music escalates]
[In German]
I'm trying to think...
How long's it been since I was here last?
I'm not sure.
It must be three weeks.
BOURNE: Yes, in Paris.
Do you have the number
for a Jason Bourne?
OPERATOR:
Yes. Would you lie me to connect you?
BOURNE: Yes, please.
BOURNE: [On answer machine]
This is 46 99 03 84.
Leave a message at the beep.
[Bourne repeating message in French]
[Tense instrumental music]
[Ambulance siren blares]
[Tram sounds horn]
[Police car sirens blare]
U.S. Citizens
BOURNE: I'm an American.
Okay.
GUARD: Hold it.
MARINE 1 : You've no jurisdiction here.
MARINE 1 : Hold it there. Okay?
MARIE: No.
Excuse me. No.
This is not my current address, oay?
This was my address until two days ago,
when I started standing in line.
Now I lose my apartment, okay?
That means no address, no phone,
no money, no time.
-And I still have no visa!
-Miss Kreutz, please.
CLERK: I must ask you
to keep your voice down.
MARIE: Excuse me. But where's the guy
that I talked to last week?
Every week it's a new person.
How am I supposed to--
I don't know who you saw last week.
MARIE: Let me help you. I'm sure I have it.
Hang on.
CLERK:
Could I have your attention for a moment?
MARIE: I have it right here. Just look at it.
CLERK: You staged an effort to circumvent
the immigration laws of the United States.
MARIE: This is a student visa now.
It's not about a green card anymore.
It's very different.
CLERK: It's not a menu. You don't just....
MARIE: I brought all this proof.
DISPATCHER: Potential suspect....
Help in assault incident.
You! Red bag! The red bag!
SECURITY CHIEF:
Stop right there! Put your hands up!
[Crowd screams]
[Fast-paced instrumental music]
[Alarm sounds]
MAN: I'm on it.
SECURITY CHIEF: Move it! Now!
Now! Move!
Alpha Unit, tae the bac stairs
and wor your way up. Bravo--
EVACUATION PLAN
SECURITY CHIEF: Move in! Move in!
MARINE 1 : Okay, clear!
SECURITY CHIEF: Suspect is--
BRAVO LEADER: Moving up staircase.
Proceeding to second floor.
SECURITY CHIEF: Alpha Unit, you're clear.
MARINE 2: Move! Move!
SECURITY CHIEF:
All Units, target may have a radio.
Go to Code 77. Over.
Code 77, copy.
MARINE 3: The floor! Down!
MARINE 4: Clear!
DANGER - DO NOT OPEN
[Alarm continues to sound]
DO NOT ENTER
MARINE 2: Go. Move up.
CONKLIN: He's in Zurich now? Right now?
ZORN: Yes. It just came in.
-They're sure it's him?
-Yes. He went to the bank.
Our source at the bank, that's who called.
CONKLIN: Come on.
But he's got to assume
we're watching the bank, right?
CONKLIN: I don't know. Come on.
I mean, he cleaned out the box.
He left a gun. What does that mean?
I said I don't know!
I liked it better when I thought he was dead.
[Cursing in German]
What are you looking at?
I heard you inside.
MARIE: What?
The consulate. I heard you talking.
I thought maybe we could help each other.
How's that?
BOURNE:
You need money. I need a ride out of here.
I'm not running a car service. Thank you.
I'll give you $10,000 to drive me to Paris.
[In German]
What, do you think I'm a fool?
You'd be a fool not to take it.
MARIE: Is this a joke? Some kind of scam?
BOURNE: No, it's no scam.
BOURNE: I'll give you another $10,000
when we arrive.
MARIE: Jesus.
[Police car sirens blare]
-Is that for you?
-Look. You drive, I pay. It's that simple.
I got enough trouble, okay?
BOURNE: Okay.
Can I have my money back?
CONKLIN: All right, go. Keep going.
CONKLIN: Go.
-There! Wait!
-No, it's got to be near the end.
Come on, folks! We caught a break here!
Let's go!
COMM TECH 1 : Okay, I'm up.
COMM TECH 1 : We're getting grids.
Airline, train, hotels, hospitals.
-Who's getting the address? The street?
-Gemensheidt.
RESEARCH TECH 1 : Here we go.
I think I got it.
ZORN: Is it him?
RESEARCH TECH 2: Unreal.
RESEARCH TECH 1 : This is 38 minutes ago.
ZORN: Zurich police are looking
for an American carrying a red bank bag.
ZORN: He just tore up the embassy and
put two cops in the hospital last night.
Get everybody up. Do it now.
I want them all activated.
Wait. All of them? At the same time?
You heard me.
I want Bourne in a body bag by sundown.
CONKLIN: All right, let's get a map up here!
Come on, folks! Let's work it!
PASSWORD: XX9897
AVAILABLE AGENTS IN LOCATION
COMM TECH 1 :
The grids are getting updated.
CODE: PROFESSOR
893489CHIMP - INITIATED
LOCATING
LOCATED: BARCELONA
ENTRANCE ACCEPTED
TYPE COMMAND: ENTER
CONNECTING
PREP MODE AND ARM READY
FOR TRANSPORT
HOLD PATTERN UNTIL FURTHER NOTICE
SENDING
PREP MODE AND ARM READY
FOR TRANSPORT
HAMBURG
ACTIVATION CODE: MANHEIM
PREP MODE AND ARMlTRANSPORT ZURICH
PASSPORT CHILElIMMEDIATE DISPATCH
432ZZ45
HOLD DESTINATION ZURICH - SENDING
LOCATION: ROME
CASTEL
CONNECTING - LOCATION: ROME ITALY
TRANSMISSION CONFIRMED
LOCATION: ROME ITALY
[Pulsating instrumental music]
MARIE: ...which was fine with me
because I was ready.
After six months in Amsterdam,
you're not sure...
...if you've been there 20 minutes or years,
you now.
So I went. I took all the money I had.
I went in with friends...
...we took over this really cool surf shop
outside Biarritz, right by the water.
It was amazing.
It was just amazing for about three months,
until it turned out that this...
...jerk who had fronted us the lease
was actually shining everyone on and....
And what?
What do you mean "what"? Listen to me.
I've been speed-talking
for about 60 kilometers now.
I talk when I'm nervous.
I mean, I talk like this when I'm nervous.
-I'm gonna shut up now.
-No, don't do that.
I haven't talked to anybody in a while.
Yeah, but we're not talking. I'm talking.
You've said,
like, 10 words since we left Zurich.
Well, listening to you, it's relaxing.
I haven't slept in a while and....
And I've had this headache.
It's like a constant thing in my head...
...and it's just starting
to move to the background...
...so keep going.
Really, if you want, please keep talking.
Okay.
What kind of music do you like?
What do you like? Come on.
-You know what? Never mind.
-No, it's fine. Tell me.
What do you want to listen to?
I don't know.
Come on, it's not that hard.
What do you like? Tell me.
I don't know.
Who pays $20,000 for a ride to Paris?
Fuck it.
I can't remember anything
that happened before two weeks ago.
-Lucky you.
-No, I'm serious.
I don't know who I am.
I don't know where I'm going.
None of it.
MARIE: What? Like amnesia?
BOURNE: Yes.
MARIE: Amnesia.
Right.
-And that's the best angle of the courtyard?
-That's the only angle.
What do they have of the streets?
Or, you know, the area?
They must have something.
Hang on.
What is he doing?
Is it a game? Is he warning us?
Is it a threat?
RESEARCH TECH 1 : Sir? Look at this.
-What's that?
-It's an angle of the street, a sort of alley.
Just enhance it.
Now, who the hell is that?
RESEARCH TECH 2: Marie Helena Kreutz.
She's 26, born outside Hanover.
Her father was a welder.
He died in '87.
We still don't have the mother.
The grandmother, she's still in Hanover.
It looks like she's the anchor
for this little domestic disaster.
And there's a stepbrother.
It's tough. The girl's a gypsy.
I mean, she pops up on the grid
here and there, but it's chaotic at best.
She paid some electric bills in Spain, '95.
Had a phone in her name
for three months in Belgium, '96.
No taxes, no credit.
I don't like her. I want to go deep.
Get a phone log for Granny
and the half-brother.
Anybody we can cross-file.
I want to now every place she's slept
in the past six years.
Have Paris get these out in the field.
TREADSTONE SAFE HOUSE
PARIS, FRANCE
BOURNE: I'm not maing this up.
These are real.
Okay.
Who has a safety deposit box full of...
...money and six passports and a gun?
BOURNE: Who has a bank account number
in their hip?
I come in here, and the first thing I'm doing
is I'm catching the sightlines...
...and looking for an exit.
I see the exit sign, too. I'm not worried.
MARIE: I mean, you were shot.
People do all inds of weird
and amazing stuff when they are scared.
I can tell you the license plate numbers
of all six cars outside.
I know that our waitress is left-handed...
...and the guy sitting at the counter weighs
215 pounds and can handle himself.
I now the best place to loo for a gun
is the cab of the gray truc outside.
At this altitude, I can run flat out for
a half-mile before my hands start shaking.
Now why would I know that?
How can I know that
and not know who I am?
[Soft instrumental music]
PARIS 103 - LILLE 350
[Birds chirping]
Hey.
BOURNE: I slept.
-I can't believe it.
-Yeah, well, you were tired.
I haven't slept.
Oh, here. For $20,000,
I like to throw in breakfast.
Did you stop for gas?
You were pretty out of it.
So, do you think there's,
like, a family waiting for you?
I don't know.
I've thought about it.
MARIE: Is that it?
104.
Yeah, that's the address.
No, keep going. Keep going.
-Okay. Where?
-Just take a left. Pull in over here.
MARIE: Okay.
MARIE: So, this is it, right?
Yeah, I guess.
God, I don't recognize any of this.
Okay. I should go.
Jason?
Oh, God. The money. Right.
Yeah.
BOURNE: Here.
Thank you. Okay.
Thanks for the ride.
Anytime.
Well, you could come up.
I mean, or you can wait here.
-I can go check it out. But you could wait.
-Oh, no, no.
BOURNE: You could wait.
With you, you would probably
just forget about me if I stayed here.
How could I forget about you?
You're the only person I know.
Yeah. That's true.
I guess you're not home.
[Bourne rattles door]
Monsieur Bourne, there you are.
CONCIERGE: [In French]
Monsieur Bourne, I was wondering--
I haven't seen you.
Uh, here I am.
BOURNE: [In French]
I think I forgot my key.
[Church bells ring in distance]
Hello?
MARIE: Are you sure this is all yours?
BOURNE: I guess.
BOURNE: This is my kitchen.
MARIE: Any clues?
BOURNE:
I think I'm in the shipping business.
So it's all coming back?
Do you mind if I use the bathroom?
Sure.
Okay.
[Speaking in French]
Yeah. Hello? Hello?
OPERATOR: Yes, sir, Hotel Regina, Paris.
How may I direct your call?
BOURNE: Yeah, you're in Paris?
OPERATOR: Yes, sir.
I'm looking for a guest there.
A Jason Bourne.
OPERATOR: One moment, please.
BOURNE: Thank you.
OPERATOR: I'm afraid I have no one
by that name registered.
Okay. Thank you.
Wait! No, no. Are you there? Hello?
OPERATOR: Sir?
BOURNE: Can you check
another name for me, please?
Here, bear with me one second.
BOURNE: John Kane. Kane with a "K."
OPERATOR: One moment, sir.
Thank you.
MANAGER: You call about Monsieur Kane?
John Michael Kane?
BOURNE: Yeah, that's right.
MANAGER: You are a friend of his?
BOURNE: Yeah.
MANAGER:
I have some very bad news for you, sir.
I'm sorry to tell you this, but Monsieur Kane
has passed away almost two weeks ago.
There was an accident. On the motorway.
Apparently, he was illed instantly.
Really, I'm terribly sorry
to be the one to tell you this.
When they came for his things,
it was made nown for us, you see?
BOURNE: Who came?
MANAGER: His brother.
Did his brother leave a number
or a way to get in touch with him?
MANAGER: I think not.
No, I'm sorry.
[Suspenseful music]
MARIE: Jason? There's no hot water.
It's freezing.
I'll go try the water in the kitchen.
Why don't you just stay in the bathroom?
I'll see if I can get it hot.
[Tense instrumental music]
Yeah, it's really cold in here, too.
MARIE: The water is still cold.
Yeah, it's cold in the kitchen, too.
I got it running, though.
So....
What?
Nothing.
Are you okay?
Yeah.
MARIE: What is it?
Something wrong?
[Rapid machine-gun fire]
MARIE: Jason!
[Fast-paced instrumental music]
BOURNE: Open that. Tell me what's inside.
Who are you?
ARMED AND DANGEROUS
MARIE: Oh, my God.
[Bourne questions him in many languages]
God.
BOURNE: Answer me! Who are you?
-He's got my picture!
-All right. Hang on.
MARIE: This is Zurich, yesterday!
BOURNE: Don't--
I don't know. Where did you get this?
BOURNE: Stay there.
MARIE: How did you get my picture?
MARIE: Where did you get this from?
How did you get my.... My God!
I'll do this! You stay there. Stay there!
[Car tires screech, pedestrians scream]
-Where are your shoes? Get your shoes.
-Sure. Yeah, sure.
He went out the window.
Why would someone do that?
BOURNE: We can't stay here. It's not safe.
I can get us out of here, but we got to go.
We got to go right now.
[Breathlessly] Okay, look, you can wait.
You can wait for the cops. It's okay.
You just wait for them to get here.
But I can't. I got to go.
Marie?
BOURNE: Marie?
[Marie groans]
BOURNE: Quiet. Be quiet.
[Marie vomits]
Don't look.
[Indistinct chatter]
[Ambulance siren blares]
[Fast-paced instrumental music]
[Dialing phone number]
OPERATIVE: Code in.
NICKY: Alpha 37509.
[Phone rings]
ZORN: Yeah.
Hang on.
Bourne went to Paris, to the apartment.
CONKLIN: We got him? Tell me.
NICKY: He illed our man.
CONKLIN: What? In the apartment?
NICKY: Yeah.
CONKLIN: Well, you got to clean that up.
NICKY: No, I can't clean it up.
NICKY: There's a body in the street.
CONKLIN: So?
There's police. This is Paris.
CONKLIN: Put up the scanners.
Get as much radio information as you can.
Okay, you stay here.
I'm gonna go find a place for this money.
I'll be back in 10 minutes.
[Train announcements in French]
BOURNE: Hey, I told you to stay in the car.
Jesus Christ. I told you to stay in the car.
I needed a drink.
I didn't think you would come back.
Look, you got to go to the cops.
Right now.
You got to go before this gets any worse.
MARIE: By myself?
BOURNE: It's gonna be okay.
You're gonna take my passport, okay?
You show this to them.
You have that picture, you have the $20,000.
You tell them everything that happened.
They'll believe you.
They have to believe you.
Marie, you can't just sit here.
It's not safe here.
MARIE: Safe?
This is from inside the embassy.
-Who can do this? This is from yesterday.
-I don't know.
MARIE: How can they know we're together?
BOURNE: I'm trying to do the right thing.
BOURNE: That's all.
MARIE: Right?
How'll you make this right
by sending me there alone?
You think I want you to go to the cops?
That's good?
-You want to go, fine.
-If you go, I run!
-You tell them what happened!
-I don't know what happened!
I don't know who this guy was
or about that picture!
I don't know who I am!
Look, I'm....
You think I'm trying to burn you.
I'm trying to do the right thing.
Nobody does the right thing.
Look, I can't run with you. I can't.
We run, I got to live like this. I got to....
I don't even know who I'm hiding from.
These people know who I am.
Yeah, I got to stay here.
I got to figure this out.
So figure it out.
You take care of this car?
What do you mean?
The tires felt a little splashy
on the way over here.
MARIE: It pulls a little to the right.
POLICE
[Dialogue over police radio]
[Police car sirens blare]
Last chance, Marie.
[Rock music plays on radio]
[Tires screech]
[Police car sirens blare]
[Fast-paced instrumental music]
BOURNE: So....
MARIE: What?
BOURNE: We got a bump coming up.
[Fast-paced music continues]
Turn your head away. Turn your head away.
[Cars honk repeatedly]